MAËL BOCCARDI

Quantitative Analysis | Data Science | Economics

EXPERIENCE

Quantitative Analyst - Ofi Invest Asset Management

May 2024 - Nov 2024

Paris, France

- Internship with Mr. Simon Mauffrey, focusing on quant model validation.
- Testing and monitoring of models, including mathematical and programming inspection.
- Developed a stress test model for corporate debt via Merton model.
- Conducting research in NLP methods and models.

Quantitative Analyst - NATIXIS INVESTMENT MANAGERS

m Sep 2022 - Oct 2023

Paris, France

- Apprenticeship with Mr. Olivier Russel, focusing on tools and portfolio constructions, with emphasis on Risk Parity funds.
- Research in systematic allocation based on economic regimes.
- Back-tested retirement fund allocation & performance attribution.
- Worked on technical indicators & option strategies' greek calculation.

Trader Assistant Intern - AQUAE CAPITAL

₩ July 2022 - Sep 2022

Marseille, France

- Internship with Mr. Richard Schoeb, focusing on updated performance data & indicator construction.
- Built a risk alert model based on market context and asset behavior.
- Gained insight into equity portfolio risk management and options hedging.

Quantitative Research Intern - Aix-Marseille School of Economics

May 2022 - Jun 2023

- Conducted a comprehensive study on asset class volatility inter-dependencies, manipulating and analyzing data using R Studio.
- Utilized GARCH models to calculate and extract volatility from factors to developed an error-correction model to express volatility relationships.

EDUCATION

CFA Program - Université Paris-Dauphine - PSL

2024

Paris, France

• Fixed Income, Economics, Portfolio Management, and Derivative.

Magistère Economist Engineer - Master Quantitative Finance - Aix-Marseille School of Economics - Centrale Méditerranée

2023

Marseille, France

 Dual Degree with Honors in Computer Science, Big Data, Market Finance, Econometrics, Macro/Microeconomics, Time Serie Econometrics, Stochastic Mathematics, Risk & Uncertainty, Fx Derivatives, and Risk Management.

Master of Science - University of Kent (exchange semester)

♥ Canterbury, United Kingdom

• Focus on Financial Economics, CAPM & Factor models, Econometric Methods, Macroeconomics, and Microeconomics.

- +33619872950
- @ mael.boccardi@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/maël-boccardi/
- % https://mtbcd.github.io/Portfolio-Website/

ABOUT ME

With experience as a Quantitative Analyst at Natixis IM and Ofi Invest AM, I specialize in Python-based financial models. I possess skills in econometrics, risk management, and portfolio construction, backed by a Master's in quantitative finance and the validation of CFA program at Paris Dauphine University. I'm eager about applying my expertise to quantitative challenges in the financial industry.

SKILLS

Quantitative Analysis	Data Science
Financial Modeling Risk Management	
Python R SQL	Econometrics
Machine Learning English LaTex	
Portfolio Construction French	

PROJECTS

- Stress-Test Merton Model
- Developed a tool to calculate the impact of market and environmental changes on cross-asset portfolios, focusing on credit spreads and price adjustments. Combined an equity stress test with a fixed-income stress test for comprehensive analysis.
- Regression Analysis and Data Visualization
- Studied the intricate dynamics between gold and cryptocurrency, using GARCH model for volatility estimation, ARDL for impact assessment, and VAR models.
- Programming for Portfolio Construction
- Developed programs for various portfolio constructions: Min-Var, Eq-Weighted, Mean-Var, Risk Parity, HRP.
- Master's Thesis on Regime-Based Dynamic Allocation
- Focused on developing a multi-factor (CAPM, AQR) portfolio optimization method that adapts its allocation based on macroeconomic conditions.

INTERESTS

- Sport (athleticism, climbing, snorkeling, skateboard)
- Reading & Poetry
- Travels (Asia, North America, Europe)